<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Windows XP | ALEX BABAN]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.alexbaban.com/blog/categories/windows-xp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.alexbaban.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-13T13:39:58-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.alexbaban.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Baban]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy as Path for Windows XP or Later]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.alexbaban.com/blog/2013/12/05/copy-as-path-for-windows-xp-or-later/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T12:46:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.alexbaban.com/blog/2013/12/05/copy-as-path-for-windows-xp-or-later</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many times, during my work, I need to type or paste the path of a folder or file. On Windows 7 if you &ldquo;Shift + Right-Click&rdquo; on a file or folder, you get the &ldquo;Copy as path&rdquo; option, which copies to the clipboard the complete path of the folder or file. The path is copied surrounded by double quotes. Windows XP (yes, I still use Windows XP, mostly for testing) does not have &ldquo;Copy as path&rdquo;, also on Windows 7 many times I need the path without the double quotes.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve decided to write my own small program to add &ldquo;Copy as path&rdquo; options to Windows XP and also use it on Windows 7 to get the path when I don&rsquo;t need the double quotes.</p>

<h2>CopyPath written in PureBasic</h2>

<p>PureBasic is a native 32-bit and 64-bit programming language based on established BASIC rules. The key features of PureBasic are portability (Windows, Linux and MacOS X are currently supported), the production of very fast and highly optimized executables and, of course, the very simple BASIC syntax.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve published the source code on <a href="https://github.com/alexbaban/small-projects">my GitHub &ldquo;small-projects&rdquo; repository</a> from where you can also download the executable. If you&rsquo;d like to build the program yourself from the source code, read on.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/7742321.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>; CopyPath, utility program
; It takes as argument a file or a folder, puts the path of it into clipboard
; It can be a great time saver if included into &quot;Send to&quot; menu
; This program is written in PureBasic, go to http://purebasic.com/ for the compiler/IDE
; It works similar to &quot;Copy as path&quot; feature from Windows 7
; It works on Windows XP or later

; Author: Alex Baban
; Date: 2013-03-15
; Version: 1.0.1



; make this a console program
OpenConsole()

; get the first argument (full path to file or folder)
argPath$ = ProgramParameter(0)

; put the path in clipboard as text
SetClipboardText(argPath$)

; show the path in a console window to give user feedback
PrintN(argPath$)
Delay(1000)

; end program
End</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<h2>Build CopyPath from source code</h2>

<p>To be continued&hellip;</p>

<h2>Install CopyPath</h2>

<p>To be continued&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
